<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Edwin Young</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Edwin Young</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 18:11:06 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cloud Shell, az login, and Managed Identity</title>
      <link>/blog/cloud_shell_auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 18:11:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/cloud_shell_auth/</guid>
      <description>When you open Azure Cloud Shell and run Get-AzVM or az vm list for the first time, it works right away. But why?
That may seem like an odd question. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work quite the same way when you run PowerShell or Azure CLI locally - you need to run Connect-AzAccount or az login first. So what&amp;rsquo;s the difference?
A surprising amount of things are happening behind the scenes for this to work, and at the time of writing there are some limitations you might hit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Arc command-line tools cheat sheet</title>
      <link>/blog/arc_cheat_sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 17:11:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/arc_cheat_sheet/</guid>
      <description>Arc for Servers has a new Azure CLI extension and PowerShell module. Both are still experimental, so expect a few rough edges and please report any issues you see. Because they are prerelease, they are not included (yet) in the main releases (ie, you don&amp;rsquo;t get this just by installing az cli or the Az module). However they are already functional and useful. Here&amp;rsquo;s how to do some simple operations with each of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install your own versions of tools in Azure Cloud Shell</title>
      <link>/blog/install_tools_locally/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 18:11:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/install_tools_locally/</guid>
      <description>Cloud Shell comes with a lot of tools, and we try to keep them up to date. But sometimes you need something a little bit more cutting edge or unusual. How do you install it?
Using Cloud Shell is a little different from running your own Linux computer, but it&amp;rsquo;s a lot like using a multi-user Unix system. The main difference is you are not root and we won&amp;rsquo;t tell you the root password (sorry).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Azure Cloud Shell store my command history?</title>
      <link>/blog/cloud_shell_history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 18:11:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/cloud_shell_history/</guid>
      <description>A few people have asked &amp;ldquo;Hey, uh, hypothetically, if I had typed a password or a secret at the Cloud Shell prompt, did you store it, and how would I delete it? Obviously I would never do this, asking for a friend.&amp;quot;
Relax, we&amp;rsquo;ve all done it. And the answer is &amp;ldquo;Sort of&amp;rdquo;.
In more detail, Cloud Shell does not store your history itself. But the shell you are running inside it does, unless you have configured something specially.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the difference between az account show and Get-AzContext?</title>
      <link>/blog/azcli_and_azurepowershell_context/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 17:11:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/azcli_and_azurepowershell_context/</guid>
      <description>One issue which can trip you up when using command-line tools to configure Azure is a confusing lack of interaction between Azure CLI and Azure PowerShell. They both provide a &amp;ldquo;context&amp;rdquo; so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to keep specifying the subscription over and over. But Azure CLI (the az command) has a separate context from Azure PowerShell. You can see this by running
az account show # show azure CLI context Get-AzContext # show azure Powershell context az account set --subscription &#39;mysub2&#39; # change Azure CLI context az account show # azure CLI has changed Get-AzContext # Azure PowerShell has not!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>