<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CloudShell on Edwin Young</title>
    <link>/categories/cloudshell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CloudShell on Edwin Young</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/cloudshell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How Azure Cloud Shell stores your files</title>
      <link>/blog/cloud_shell_files/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/cloud_shell_files/</guid>
      <description>The official information on Cloud Shell&amp;rsquo;s file storage is here. It&amp;rsquo;s good stuff, and covers most things you might like to know, take a look! This blog contains a few more behind-the-scenes details for the curious. NB: We might change this in the future, this isn&amp;rsquo;t guaranteed.
We can see from the docs that all your files are stored in an Azure File Share which belongs to you, and which you select when you first start CLoud Shell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cloud Shell, az login, and Managed Identity</title>
      <link>/blog/cloud_shell_auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/cloud_shell_auth/</guid>
      <description>When you open Azure Cloud Shell and run Get-AzVM or az vm list for the first time, it works right away. But why?
That may seem like an odd question. Of course it should work right away! But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work quite the same way when you run PowerShell or Azure CLI locally - you need to run Connect-AzAccount or az login first. So what&amp;rsquo;s the difference?
A surprising amount of things are happening behind the scenes for this to work, and at the time of writing there are some limitations you might hit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some environment vars in Cloud Shell</title>
      <link>/blog/vars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/vars/</guid>
      <description>Cloud Shell sets several environment variables which can be useful. Here&amp;rsquo;s a brain dump on some of the more useful ones- the list is not exhaustive. You can see them by running env. Please note this is not official documentation and these could change!
   Name Example Value Purpose     ACC_CLOUD PROD If you need to check if a script is in Cloud Shell, look for the existence of this variable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install your own versions of tools in Azure Cloud Shell</title>
      <link>/blog/install_tools_locally/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 18:11:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/install_tools_locally/</guid>
      <description>Cloud Shell comes with a lot of tools, and we try to keep them up to date. But sometimes you need something a little bit more cutting edge or unusual. How do you install it?
Using Cloud Shell is a little different from running your own Linux computer, but it&amp;rsquo;s a lot like using a multi-user Unix system. The main difference is you are not root and we won&amp;rsquo;t tell you the root password (sorry).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Azure Cloud Shell store my command history?</title>
      <link>/blog/cloud_shell_history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 18:11:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/cloud_shell_history/</guid>
      <description>A few people have asked &amp;ldquo;Hey, uh, hypothetically, if I had typed a password or a secret at the Cloud Shell prompt, did you store it, and how would I delete it? Obviously I would never do this, asking for a friend.&amp;quot;
Relax, we&amp;rsquo;ve all done it. And the answer is &amp;ldquo;Sort of&amp;rdquo;.
In more detail, Cloud Shell does not store your history itself. But the shell you are running inside it does, unless you have configured something specially.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>